The Princess Sapphire
Knight of the Ribbon
♪ Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano ♪
The dreams I see are my secret
♪ Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano ♪
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
♪ Akai manto hira hira ♪
A red cape fluttering
♪ Uma o tobasu oujo ♪
Galloping on a horse—the princess
♪ Sore ga atashi ♪
That’s me!
♪ Lula-dula-lula-dula ♪
-
♪ Lulu laa, lulaa ♪
♪ Lula-dula-lula-dula ♪
-
♪ Lulu laa, lulaa ♪
♪ Ribon no kishi wa ♪
The Knight of the Ribbon,
♪ Honto wa hontto wa ♪
Truly, truly,
♪ Atashi nano sa ♪
It’s really me!
Fifty-Second Episode
The Royal Wedding
May Silverland Be Happy
Now, before we begin today's story,
let me refresh your memory on what happened last time.
Duralumin, a pawn of the X-Union,
finally revealed his traitorous nature and
tried to kill the King, Queen, and Sapphire.
However, betrayed by Nylon,
Duralumin met a swift end, and the crown fell into Nylon's hands.
As the king of Silverland, Nylon welcomed X-Union into the castle.
Meanwhile, Sapphire bade farewell to her parents in the Skull Chamber
and escaped the castle with three orbs—gold, silver, and bronze—
believed to hold the power to protect the kingdom.
She ran to seek help from Prince Franz.
However,
the King and Queen were executed on Skull Island by the X-Union.
Three orbs...
What power do you truly hold?
If you really have power, please help Sapphire now!
Poor Sapphire...
Heavenly Father, I'll do anything.
So please, make Sapphire happy.
What's that sound of bells?
Please stop!
Stop it!
Stop! Stop it! Please stop!
Have you lost your mind, Nylon?
What's wrong?
I've learned the truth about those bells.
The people are ringing them to mourn the executed King and Queen.
What!?
Destroy every bell in the kingdom! And capture Sapphire immediately!
Find her, no matter where she hides!
Tear down mountains if you must!
Destroy every possible place Sapphire could be hiding!
We can't even hear the bells anymore...
and we've got no food or place to live.
Where on earth did Prince Sapphire go?
The King and Queen have gone to heaven, too.
But Sapphire is fine, so I'm relieved.
Is it ready yet, Tink?
Not yet, not yet!
Kuro no Ojisan is on lookout duty!
All right, Hotoru-kun, I'm counting on you!
Ahem!
Here's a gift for the two of you from our forest friends!
Here you go!
How beautiful!
It's lovely!
Sapphire!
Do you like our present?
Thank you, Tink!
It's wonderful!
See?
I'm so glad you like it!
In that case, here's a little bonus!
Hit it!
Sapphire!
I'm sorry, Tink.
Crying at a time like this...
Sapphire really is a coward.
No matter how hard I try to be brave, I'm still so sad.
I just want to see my father and mother... one more time.
So that's what happened.
Sapphire was enduring it all this time.
Heavenly Father, I'll endure whatever painful trials come my way.
So please grant my prayer.
Give Sapphire her papa and mama back.
Please bring them back to life.
I beg you, hear my prayer.
Heavenly Father!
Tink,
mukashi wa tenshi datta omae da.
- as a former angel,
negaigoto wa iu dake de kanaerareru mono de wa nai koto wo shitte iru daro.
- you know prayers aren't answered simply by speaking them.
Aisuru mono wo tasuketai no nara,
- If you want to save those you love,
sono hito no tame ni chikara no kagiri,
- work for them with all your strength
kokoro no kagiri hataraku no da.
- and all your heart.
Washi wa koko kara mite iyou.
- I shall watch over you from here.
Omae no negaigoto ga kanaerareru ka doka wa,
- Whether your prayer is answered
omae no hataraki shidai na no da.
- depends entirely on your efforts.
I'll do it!
For Sapphire's sake, I'll do anything, no matter how hard!
Wow, incredible!
Thanks so much.
Sapphire will be so happy.
Who brought this?
Nezumiko brought it.
But you can't eat this.
Oh, I know!
We can ring the bell with this!
I'll ring the bell to wake Sapphire up.
Opal!
Sapphire kept those three orbs put away so carefully!
But can't you give it back to me just for a moment?
I want to ring the bell with it and wake Sapphire up.
I'll be careful not to break it.
Thank you!
Okay, I'm gonna ring it!
It started ringing all by itself!
You attached the three jewels.
Those three jewels really do have a mysterious power.
Legend says they protect the people, the royal family, and Silverland.
Wow, it's a bell!
What happened?
I thought I told you to demolish all the bells!
Well, sir... the cause is completely unknown.
Shut up!
Stop hesitating and smash it!
What a wonderful thing!
My arms are itching for action!
I'm not gonna just stand around sulking either!
Sapphire, it's time to fight!
We're driving X out of Silverland!
Thank you, everyone!
It's X!
I've been waiting for you, X!
We've got our mysterious friend on our side!
Lets go, guys!
Opal, we're counting on you!
Lets go!
Big brothers!
Ring louder and louder!
Fools! Did you think you could defeat the X Army?!
Advance!
Trample them!
What a powerful force!
Oh no!
Serves you right!
Tink!
Got 'em! They're safe!
Hey, in here!
We're saved! We made it!
Damn it! We're trapped!
Are we going to miss dinner?!
Look, I know the exit to this cave.
It comes out right next to the castle.
I see.
All right!
Hurry!
Someone, find me a
weapon—anything will do!
I'm going to take it
and storm the castle!
That's it! We can make them using the three orbs.
That's right!
We're the top woodworkers in the world!
I see. Thank you!
Tink should have those three orbs!
Where is he?
Tink!
Where are you?
It's so hard...
It's no use...
Tink! There you are!
Tink, hang in there.
Tink!
Sapphire!
I was making a weapon with the orbs to protect Sapphire.
Thank you, Tink.
Now then, time to show of our skills as blacksmiths!
All right!
It's done!
This power is incredible!
Tink, look.
What's that!
We made it from the leftover metal!
I'm sure this horn has the same power as those metal orbs.
Blow it for us!
Okay.
Everyone, please wait here.
Sapphire!
Girls stay back!
Leave this to me!
Franz?
Hyah!
Sapphire!
Forgive me, Franz!
I can't let you put yourself in danger!
That's Sapphire! Fire!
Sapphire!
Franz!
I'm fine! Quick, run!
It's the mysterious power of the Royal Orb!
Sapphire! Now is the time to crush X!
Yay! We did it! We did it!
Curse you, Sapphire...
Sapphire!
X!
Now is the time of your demise!
So you are Sapphire?
Sapphire!
Heavenly Father! Please save Sapphire!
We did it, Sapphire!
Watch out!
Tink!
It's the end of Nylon!
Tink! Tink!
Tink!
Don't die!
You can't die!
Sapphire, it's time for us to say goodbye.
Father in Heaven is calling me.
I have to go back.
No! I don't want to say goodbye, Tink!
Father in Heaven,
I did my best for Sapphire.
Will you answer my prayer?
Yoroshi, Tink.
- Very well, Tink.
Omae no negai wo kanae yo.
- I shall answer your prayer.
Sapphire no otosan to okasan o soko e okurikaeso.
- I will send Sapphire's father and mother back to her.
Soshite, omae ga machigatte ireta
- And I will take away the boy's heart
Sapphire no otoko no kokoro wo totte age yo.
- that you wrongfully gave to Sapphire.
Thank you, Father.
Mother!
Father!
Sapphire!
Mother!
I'm Tink, back to being an angel!
What became of Silverland after that?
What happened to Sapphire and Franz?
You all want to know, don't you?
Silverland has returned to the beautiful kingdom it once was.
Did you get the plan ready for tonight?
Sorry to keep you waiting!
They say Sapphire and Franz are getting married soon.
I'm sure they'll make a wonderfully happy couple.
And I'll be attending the wedding when they do!
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
♪ Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen ♪
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
♪ Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen ♪
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
♪ Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo ♪
Even if demons come, even if storms arrive,
♪ tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai ♪
Our bonded hearts will never part.
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP